ILGWU Research Department Records 5780/105
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
ILGWU Research Department Records
1921-1983
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
Teper, Lazare
International Ladies' Garment Workers' Union
5780/105
5 cubic feet
5 linear ft.
Records (documents).
This collection contains the papers of Lazare Teper. In addition to subject files and correspondence, Teper's papers include files relating to the Wage Stabilization Board, including correspondence regarding applications to the board, compensation adjustment, approval of fringe benefits, and proposed health and welfare plans.
5516182
General
Contact Information:
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation and Archives Martin P. Catherwood Library 227 Ives Hall Cornell University Ithaca, NY 14853 (607) 255-3183 kheel_center@cornell.edu http://www.ilr.cornell.edu/library/kheel-center
Compiled by:
T. Figurasin, May 21, 2009
EAD encoding:
Kheel Staff, April 11, 2019
Biographical / Historical
The International Ladies' Garment Workers' Union was once one of the largest labor unions in the United States founded in 1900 by local union delegates representing about 2,000 members in cities in the northeastern United States. It was one of the first U.S. Unions to have a membership consisting of mostly females, and it played a key role in the labor history of the 1920s and 1930s. The union is generally referred to as the "ILGWU" or the "ILG". The ILGWU grew in geographical scope, membership size, and political influence to become one of the most powerful forces in American organized labor by mid-century. Representing workers in the women's garment industry, the ILGWU worked to improve working and living conditions of its members through collective bargaining agreements, training programs, health care facilities, cooperative housing, educational opportunities, and other efforts. The ILGWU merged with the Amalgamated Clothing and Textile Workers Union in 1995 to form the Union of Needle trades, Industrial and Textile Employees (UNITE). UNITE merged with the Hotel Employees and Restaurant Employees Union (HERE) in 2004 to create a new union known as UNITE HERE. The two unions that formed UNITE in 1995 represented only 250,000 workers between them, down from the ILGWU's peak membership of 450,000 in 1969.
Biographical / Historical
Formed in 1937, the Research Department of the International Ladies' Garment Workers' Union (ILGWU) supported the administrative operations of the Union and coordinated the ILGWU's investigative operations. It provided union leaders with information on wages, working conditions, economic conditions, and other matters in the women's garment industry; analyzed information for the union; and monitored developments in the industry.
In addition to providing research for union leadership, Research Department staff prepared materials for Congressional testimony, presented cases on behalf of local unions to the War Labor Board, and worked to administer the Fair Labor Standards Act. At times, the director of the Research Department represented the ILGWU in national forums.
The Department also maintained an extensive library, collecting and housing documents from Union administrative staff that were deemed substantive and of lasting value to the Union, whether produced internally or externally. The information gathered by the Department was of particular value during labor disputes and contract negotiations.
Lazare Teper was the founding director of the ILGWU's Research Department, working in that position from 1937 to 1980. Born in Russia sometime between 1906 and 1908, Teper later studied at the University of Paris and earned his doctorate at Johns Hopkins University. He died in New York City in 1985.
Scope and Contents
The Research Department records reflect the department's varied functions, documenting its role in gathering and analyzing information for international and local union leadership, representing the union before government and labor organizations, and gathering materials of research, and oftentimes historical, value. Some segments of the records focus on one aspect of the department's work, and others include documentation across the department's functions.
Research Department director Lazare Teper's papers, for example, include files relating to the Wage Stabilization Board (5780/105). The department also maintained records focused on the National Coat and Suit Industry Board (statements of receipts and disbursements, label division reports, meetings minutes, bulletins to members, and other reports and resolutions), as well as some related legal files (5780/123). Also among the documents collected by the Research Department are the New York Coat and Suit Industry Reports between 1934 and 1960. (5780/168)
Parts of the Research Department records consist primarily of collected documents from ILGWU affiliates. In this way, they resemble and, in some instances, complement the parts of the Archives Department Records (5780/121, 5780/121 PUBS), records generated by local unions (Series III), and the general collection of ILGWU publications (5780 PUBS). Research Department records of this kind contain records of predecessor unions to the ILGWU and ILGWU local union records (5780/045), or the annual report, "Conditions in the Women's Clothing Industry" (5780/078).
Other parts of the Research Department records document all of the department's functions. These records include financial and administrative reports, meeting minutes, and correspondence (5780/056, 5780/209), collected printed material (5780/168), and ILGWU statements on issues related to the garment industry (5780/209).
This collection contains the papers of Lazare Teper. In addition to subject files and correspondence, Teper's papers include files relating to the Wage Stabilization Board, including correspondence regarding applications to the board, compensation adjustment, approval of fringe benefits, and proposed health and welfare plans.
Conditions Governing Access
Access to the collections in the Kheel Center is restricted. Please contact a reference archivist for access to these materials.
Related Materials
Related Collections: 5780: ILGWU records 5780/045: ILGWU Research Department Records 5780/056: ILGWU Research Department Collected Documents 5780/078: ILGWU Research Department Reports 5780/123: ILGWU Research Department Records 5780/168: ILGWU Research Department Records 5780/209: ILGWU Research Department Records
Women's clothing industry -- United States; Clothing workers -- Labor unions -- United States; Clothing workers -- United States; Industrial relations -- United States; Teper, Lazare, 1908-; International Ladies' Garment Workers' Union. Research Dept.
5516182
- Gold Manufacturing Company, 1951 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Oneita Knitting Mills, 1951 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  Scope and Contents
  May 31 - July 18
- Metal Findings Corporation, 1951-1952 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Knitted Accessory Group, 1952 (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Malden Spinning and Dyeing, 1951-1952 (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Lord and Taylor, 1951 (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Original Embroideries, 1952 (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Gerson and Kaplan [Part 1 of 2], 1952 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  Includes copies of proposal increases.
- Gerson and Kaplan [Part 2 of 2], 1952 (Box 1, Folder 9)
- Moss Cane Incorporated, 1952 (Box 1, Folder 10)
- Minnesota Apparel - Cloak Division, 1952 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  Paramount Coat Company and Barnett Coat Company
- Minnesota Apparel - Dress Division, 1952 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  Mar Jo Dress Company, Juliette Originals, Kahn Dress, Jean Lang Dress, A. Fine Originals, Fairchild Manufacturing, Charles Pearlman Dress Company, Stylerite Dress Company, and Perry Brown Incorporated.
- McKettrick-Williams, 1952 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  Pittston Dress
- J.T. Flagg Knitting Company, Incorporated, 1952 (Box 1, Folder 14)
- Palmerton Blouse Company, 1952 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  Newly organized shop.
- National Blouse Company, 1952 (Box 1, Folder 16)
- Glenwear, 1952 (Box 1, Folder 17)
- Gap Mills, 1952 (Box 1, Folder 18)
- Nite Kraft Corporation, 1952 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  Shamokin Local 185.
- Four's Manufacturing Company, 1953 (Box 1, Folder 20)
- Mid-American Manufacturing Company, 1952 (Box 1, Folder 21)
- General Knitting Mills, 1952 (Box 1, Folder 22)
  Regarding vacation money
- Harris-Hogan Company, 1952 (Box 1, Folder 23)
- Nite Kraft Corporation, 1952 (Box 1, Folder 24)
  Regarding the Newark, New Jersey and Orange, New Jersey plants.
- Loungeray, 1952 (Box 1, Folder 25)
  Robes division
- Kain-Murphy, 1952 (Box 1, Folder 26)
  Underwear division. Proposals by the Signal Knitting Mills and the Ilena Mills.
- Nord-Ray Belt Manufacturing, 1952 (Box 1, Folder 27)
- Jack Keller Company, 1952 (Box 1, Folder 28)
- Gottfried Company, 1952 (Box 1, Folder 29)
- M.G. Kinsler Company, 1952 (Box 1, Folder 30)
- Gem Rubber Company [Part 1 of 2], 1950-1952 (Box 1, Folder 31)
- Gem Rubber Company [Part 2 of 2], 1950-1952 (Box 1, Folder 32)
- J. Kaplan, 1943 (Box 1, Folder 33)
- Kenrose Manufacturing Company, 1952 (Box 1, Folder 34)
- Jean Frocks, Incorporated, 1952 (Box 1, Folder 35)
- Julius Kayser and Company, 1952 (Box 1, Folder 36)
  Regarding the plant in Allentown, Pennsylvania.
- Klear-Vu Products Corporation, 1952 (Box 1, Folder 37)
- Maiden Form Brassiere Company, Incorporated, 1953 (Box 1, Folder 38)
- Maynor Manufacturing, 1953 (Box 1, Folder 39)
- Ladies' Apparel Retailers Guild II, 1943-1944 (Box 1, Folder 40)
- Gordon Brothers Manufacturing, 1943 (Box 1, Folder 41)
- Lark Dress Company, 1944 (Box 1, Folder 42)
- Industrial Association of Juvenile Apparel, 1953 (Box 1, Folder 43)
- Jay Thorpe, Incorporated, 1952 (Box 1, Folder 44)
- Chevron Manufacturing Company, 1952 (Box 2, Folder 1)
- Augusta Knitting Mills, 1951 (Box 2, Folder 2)
- Alkon Photo Products, Incorporated, 1952 (Box 2, Folder 3)
- Belt Association, 1951 (Box 2, Folder 4)
- Atlas Crafts Company, 1951-1952 (Box 2, Folder 5)
- F.W. Breuss Manufacturing Company, 1951 (Box 2, Folder 6)
- Augusta Knitting Corporation, 1952 (Box 2, Folder 7)
- Association of Men's Belts, 1951 (Box 2, Folder 8)
- National Association of Women's Belt Manufacturers, 1951 (Box 2, Folder 9)
- Vicmore Belt Company, 1951 (Box 2, Folder 10)
- Stelzer Brothers, Incorporated, 1951 (Box 2, Folder 11)
- S and G Leather Goods Corporation, 1951 (Box 2, Folder 12)
- Rosanne Belt Company, 1950 (Box 2, Folder 13)
- Olympic Belt and Button Corporation, 1950 (Box 2, Folder 14)
- Metropolitan Button Works, 1951 (Box 2, Folder 15)
- Hygrade Belt Company, 1951 (Box 2, Folder 16)
- Handa Belts, Incorporated, 1950 (Box 2, Folder 17)
- Goodman Belt Company, 1951 (Box 2, Folder 18)
- Garay and Company, 1951 (Box 2, Folder 19)
- Elegant Leather Goods Company, 1951 (Box 2, Folder 20)
- Champion Belt Company, 1951 (Box 2, Folder 21)
- Calderon Belt and Bags, 1951 (Box 2, Folder 22)
- Burke Leather Company, 1951 (Box 2, Folder 23)
- Bert Len Novelty Company, Incorporated (Leslie), 1951 (Box 2, Folder 24)
- Belmo Fashions, Incorporated, 1950-1951 (Box 2, Folder 25)
- Action Novelty, 1951 (Box 2, Folder 26)
- Belt Productions Company, 1951 (Box 2, Folder 27)
- Frank and Raymond, 1951 (Box 2, Folder 28)
- Dave Fleishman, 1951 (Box 2, Folder 29)
- Creative Novelties, 1951 (Box 2, Folder 30)
- Levine and Axelrod, 1951 (Box 2, Folder 31)
- Men's Beltwear, Incorporated, 1951 (Box 2, Folder 32)
- P.M. Belt Company, 1951 (Box 2, Folder 33)
- Krasnow Belt Company, 1951 (Box 2, Folder 34)
- The Jewett Manufacturing Company - Independent Men's Belts, 1951 (Box 2, Folder 35)
- York Belt Company, 1951 (Box 2, Folder 36)
- Julie Novelty Company, 1951 (Box 2, Folder 37)
- Desley Fabrics, 1951 (Box 2, Folder 38)
- Fine Art Pillow, 1951 (Box 2, Folder 39)
- Eastern Bag, 1951 (Box 2, Folder 40)
- A. Burrascano, 1952 (Box 2, Folder 41)
- Clearview Products, 1952 (Box 2, Folder 42)
- Leslie Fay Fashions, Incorporated, 1952 (Box 2, Folder 43)
- Allison Manufacturing Company, Incorporated, 1952 (Box 2, Folder 44)
- Dutchess Underwear, 1952 (Box 2, Folder 45)
- Abbey Record Corporation, 1952 (Box 2, Folder 46)
- Associated Corset and Brassiere Manufacturers, 1950 (Box 2, Folder 47)
- Bennet Textile Company, Incorporated, 1952 (Box 2, Folder 48)
  Correspondence
- Emkay, 1952 (Box 2, Folder 49)
- Archbald Sewing Company, 1952 (Box 2, Folder 50)
- Famous Infant's Knitwear, 1952 (Box 2, Folder 51)
- Berne Knitting Company, 1951 (Box 2, Folder 52)
- Consolidated Retail Stores, 1952 (Box 2, Folder 53)
- Character Foundations, Incorporated, 1952 (Box 2, Folder 54)
- Atlanta Dress Manufacturer's Association, 1953 (Box 2, Folder 55)
  Atlanta Dress includes R.D. Gilleland Dress Manufacturing Company, Gordon Dress Company, Billie Bee Dress Manufacturing Company, Ray Shire Dress, Majestic Manufacturing Company, Saul Klenberg, Dixie Dress Manufacturing Company, Levy Brothers, Le Ray Frocks, Lee Dress Manufacturing Company, Rita Dress Company, Bressler Brothers.
- Associated Novelties Corporation, 1943 (Box 2, Folder 56)
- Champion Belt Manufacturing Company, 1943-1944 (Box 2, Folder 57)
- Belt Association, Incorporated, 1952 (Box 2, Folder 58)
- Belt Cases (Box 2, Folder 59)
  Miscellaneous notes on different manufacturing companies.
- Atlanta Dress Manufacturer's Association, 1952-1953 (Box 2, Folder 60)
- Bon Dana Sportswear Company, 1953 (Box 2, Folder 61)
- Hand Covered Buckle and Novelty Association, 1951 (Box 2, Folder 62)
- Independent Buckle (Box 2, Folder 63)
- Independent Cut-Up Belt Firms, 1951 (Box 2, Folder 64)
- Independent Men's Belts, 1951 (Box 2, Folder 65)
  Independent Men's Belts include Beltwear, Inc, Jewett Manufacturing Company, Krasnow Company, P.M. Belt Company, and York Belt Company, Incorporated.
- CIO Wage Stabilization Guide, 1951 (Box 2, Folder 66)
  Guidebook.
- Proposed Revision of General Regulation 5, 1951 (Box 2, Folder 67)
  Draft
- Government Contracts [Part 1 of 2] (Box 2, Folder 68)
- Government Contracts [Part 2 of 2] (Box 2, Folder 69)
- Agenda [Part 1 of 2], 1959-1960 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  Includes two surveys on consumer expenditures.
- Agenda [Part 2 of 2] (Box 3, Folder 2)
  Includes a summary of the report and recommendations of the Price Statistics Review Committee and an appendix to accompany testimony of Commissioner of Labor Statistics. Undated.
- Booklets about Wages, 1926-1961 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  Various booklets by different authors from different organizations.
- Bulletins, 1942-1968 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  Labor Information Bulletin, Must We Have a Depression, and Your Social Security.
- Bureau of Agricultural Economics, 1951 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  Technical report for the Bureau of Agricultural Economics.
- Bureau of Labor Statistics (BLS) [Part 1 of 2], 1963 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  Regarding the Consumer Price Index
- Bureau of Labor Statistics (BLS) [Part 2 of 2], 1963 (Box 3, Folder 7)
- Bureau of the Budget, 1954 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  Regarding the formation of a committee to re-examine Federal employment and unemployment estimates.
- Commentary on the Report of the Price Statistics Review Committee, 1961 (Box 3, Folder 9)
  Includes introductory remarks and critiques.
- Conditions in the Women's Garment Industry [Part 1 of 2], 1961 (Box 3, Folder 10)
  Report
- Conditions in the Women's Garment Industry [Part 2 of 2], 1966-1967 (Box 3, Folder 11)
- Consumer Price Index (Box 3, Folder 12)
  Excerpts regarding the CPI. Undated.
- Current Population Survey Materials [Part 1 of 4], 1946-1948 (Box 3, Folder 13)
  Reports on results and how the CPS was done.
- Current Population Survey Materials [Part 2 of 4], 1954 (Box 3, Folder 14)
  Various statistics.
- Current Population Survey Materials [Part 3 of 4], 1954 (Box 3, Folder 15)
  List of CPS materials.
- Current Population Survey Materials [Part 4 of 4] (Box 3, Folder 16)
- Current Population Reports [Part 1 of 2], 1954 (Box 3, Folder 17)
- Current Population Reports [Part 2 of 2], 1952 (Box 3, Folder 18)
  Report and Recommendations
- Discussion of the Arnow Paper, 1960 (Box 3, Folder 19)
  A foreign trade and collective bargaining article by Lazere Teper.
- Enumeration and Area Design [Part 1 of 4], 1952-1952 (Box 3, Folder 20)
  Regarding 68-area and 230-area designs.
- Enumeration and Area Design [Part 2 of 4], 1952-1954 (Box 3, Folder 21)
- Enumeration and Area Design [Part 3 of 4], 1951 (Box 3, Folder 22)
  Regarding 68-area design. Includes Current Population Survey "How-to" lists.
- Enumeration and Area Design [Part 4 of 4], 1950-1951 (Box 3, Folder 23)
  District Supervisor's manuals
- Geneva Textile Meeting, 1961 (Box 3, Folder 24)
- Income Distribution in the United States, 1967 (Box 3, Folder 25)
  Excerpt from the Journal of Marketing Research
- Income Distribution Trends in Latin America, 1969 (Box 3, Folder 26)
  Seminar on the labor issue and the planning process.
- Labor Terms, 1964 (Box 3, Folder 27)
  Dictionary of labor terms in different languages. Created by the Office of International Labor Affairs of the U.S. Department of Labor.
- Lazare Teper Personal, 1937-1943 (Box 3, Folder 28)
  Teper's personal notes and correspondence.
- Lazare Teper Reports and Articles, 1939-1948 (Box 3, Folder 29)
- Learner Regulations, 1958 (Box 3, Folder 30)
- Limitations of the Existing Productivity Measures, 1946 (Box 3, Folder 31)
  Reports
- Mission to Mexico, 1967 (Box 3, Folder 32)
  Investigation of the shifts that have taken place in the distribution of income.
- Notes and Pending Legislation, 1965 (Box 3, Folder 33)
  Puerto Rico
- Prehearing Statement, 1960 (Box 3, Folder 34)
  Before the Special Industry Committee No. 48A for Puerto Rico.
- Price Statistics, 1960 (Box 3, Folder 35)
- Report of Price Statistics Review Committee [Part 1 of 2], 1960 (Box 3, Folder 36)
- Report of Price Statistics Review Committee [Part 2 of 2], 1961 (Box 3, Folder 37)
- Samuel Gompers (Box 3, Folder 38)
  Three booklets about Samuel Gompers.
- Training of Enumerators [Part 1 of 2], 1953 (Box 3, Folder 39)
  Training program for Current Population Survey revision.
- Training of Enumerators [Part 2 of 2], 1954 (Box 3, Folder 40)
- Unemployment Compensation Commission, 1948 (Box 3, Folder 41)
  In the matter of the proposed private plan regulations.
- A Trade Unionist Looks at Financial Statements (Box 4, Folder 1)
  Essay by William Gomberg, Director Management Engineering Department of the ILGWU. Undated.
- Amendments to the Fair Labor Standards Act, 1970 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  By Lazare Teper. Statement presented before the Labor Committee on Education and Labor.
- American Statistical Association, 1943 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  Appraisal of the U.S. Bureau of Labor Statistics Cost of Living Index.
- Apparel (Knit and Woven) Domestic and Import, 1964 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  Brief before the Trade Information Committee.
- Apparel (Knit and Woven) Imports, 1975 (Box 4, Folder 5)
  Report before the Trade Policy Staff Committee.
- Aspects of Industrial Homework in Apparel Trades, 1941 (Box 4, Folder 6)
  By Lazare Teper and Nathan Weinberg.
- Bobbin, 1969 (Box 4, Folder 7)
  The management magazine of the needle trades. Regarding employee benefit and personnel policies survey.
- Brassieres from the Dominican Republic, 1978 (Box 4, Folder 8)
  Report regarding re-imposition of quotas on brassieres from the Dominican Republic.
- Bureau of Labor Statistics, 1944 (Box 4, Folder 9)
  Statements. Includes a speech delivered by George Meany.
- College Correspondence, 1975 (Box 4, Folder 10)
  Regarding CPI.
- Conditions in the Women's Garment Industry [Part 1 of 4], 1951-1952 (Box 4, Folder 11)
- Conditions in the Women's Garment Industry [Part 2 of 4], 1952-1961 (Box 4, Folder 12)
- Conditions in the Women's Garment Industry [Part 3 of 4], 1961-1970 (Box 4, Folder 13)
- Conditions in the Women's Garment Industry [Part 4 of 4], 1970-1980 (Box 4, Folder 14)
- Domestic Apparel Industry, 1968 (Box 4, Folder 15)
  By Milton Fried and Lazare Teper. Regarding economic background and impact of imports.
- Domestic Women's and Children's Apparel Industry and Multilateral Trade, 1975 (Box 4, Folder 16)
  Before the Trade Policy Staff Committee.
- Economic Conditions and Imports in Apparel Industry, 1967 (Box 4, Folder 17)
  Analysis by Teper and Fried before the Tariff Commission of the United States.
- European Economic Community and Hong Kong Agreement, 1978 (Box 4, Folder 18)
  Regarding bilateral textile agreements.
- Evaluation of the Cost of Living Index (Box 4, Folder 19)
  Report by A. N. Towson. Undated.
- Fair Labor Standards Act (Box 4, Folder 20)
  Discussion by Teper. The Social and Economic Implications of the Fair Labor Standards Act: An Interpretation in Terms of Social Costs. Undated.
- Federal Minimum Wage Legislation to Puerto Rico, 1976 (Box 4, Folder 21)
  Conference
- Federal Trade Commission (Box 4, Folder 22)
  Regarding free trade. Includes a review of the "Staff Report on Effects of Restrictions on United States Import" by W. Dulka and R. O'Sullivan. Undated.
- Firms Manufacturing Women's and Children's Garments, 1961 (Box 4, Folder 23)
  Reports and statistics.
- Forty-Cent Minimum Wage, 1941 (Box 4, Folder 24)
  Memorandum by Teper
- General Agreement on Tariffs and Trade, 1982 (Box 4, Folder 25)
  Correspondence regarding international textile fields.
- Impact of Imports, 1961-1982 (Box 4, Folder 26)
- In Opposition of Duty Reductions, 1975 (Box 4, Folder 27)
  Statement by Sol C. Chaikin submitted to the United States International Trade Commission.
- Income Distribution and Index Numbers, 1974-1975 (Box 4, Folder 28)
  Analyses
- Job Vacancies, 1966 (Box 4, Folder 29)
  Regarding Rochester and Monroe County in New York.
- Lazare Teper Resume (Box 4, Folder 30)
  Educational and occupational background, as well as list of publications. Undated.
- Mergers and Acquisitions, 1961 (Box 4, Folder 31)
  List of companies involved in recent mergers or acquisitions.
- Miscellaneous (Box 4, Folder 32)
  A document regarding California music, an invitation from the Veterans of the Office of Strategic Services, and midpoint computation.
- Multifiber Agreements, 1977 (Box 4, Folder 33)
  Report on its background and shortcomings.
- National Bureau of Economic Research, 1976 (Box 4, Folder 34)
  Correspondence and report entitled "Toward Rational Accounting in an Era of Unstable Money."
- New York City Sales and Business Tax Statistics, 1955 (Box 4, Folder 35)
  Interim report by the New York City Committee on Statistical Program
- Outlook on Women's Garment Industry, 1961-1977 (Box 4, Folder 36)
  Various reports on future trends, prospects, and outlook on the women's garment industry.
- Press Release, 1977 (Box 4, Folder 37)
  Regarding a meeting with President Jimmy Carter about imports and the Multifiber Textile Agreement.
- Puerto Rico and Mexico [Part 1 of 2], 1967-1976 (Box 4, Folder 38)
  Various reports and correspondence.
- Puerto Rico and Mexico [Part 2 of 2], 1967-1976 (Box 4, Folder 39)
- Railroad Wages, 1938 (Box 4, Folder 40)
  Report entitled "Why the Cost of Living Index Should Not Be Used as a Basis for Adjusting Railroad Wages."
- Readings on Legal Methods [Part 1 of 2], 1930 (Box 4, Folder 41)
  Selected by Walter Wheeler Cook. Professor of Law, Institute of Law, The Johns Hopkins University.
- Readings on Legal Methods [Part 2 of 2], 1930 (Box 4, Folder 42)
- Sampling Memoranda [Part 1 of 2], 1947-1948 (Box 4, Folder 43)
  Describes a research program. Memoranda numbers 1 through 4.
- Sampling Memoranda [Part 2 of 2], 1948-1949 (Box 4, Folder 44)
  Memoranda numbers 5 through 7.
- Season's Greetings, 1980 (Box 4, Folder 45)
  Greeting cards from Lazare Teper.
- State Distribution of Domestic Employment, 1962 (Box 4, Folder 46)
  Supplement to a 1962 Bureau of Labor Statistics report.
- Statement before Health Needs of the Nation, 1952 (Box 4, Folder 47)